# **Bertrand Mutangana Ishimwe**

# **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

mutanganabertrand@amail.com |GitHub|LinkedIn|Twitter | Medium|My portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Solution-driven Full-stack web developer who is adept at contributing to the highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using React, TypeScript, Ruby, and Ruby on Rails. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 1+ years, meeting the highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations, and databases.

## **SKILLS**

**Front-End**: JavaScript,TypeScript, Next, React, Redux, jQuery, Html5, Css, Sass, Tailwind, Bootstrap, UI/UX **Back-End**: Ruby, Ruby On Rails, MySql, PostgreSQL

**Tools & Methods**: Git, GitHub, GitLab, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, AWS, and cloud storage

**Professional**: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Leadership, mentoring, software documentation, maintenance and repair, attention to detail.

# **EXPERIENCE**

MICROVERSE

# **Technical Support Engineer**

California, US (Remote)

May 2022 - Present

- Provided technical support to 100+ students, ensuring that they follow project guidelines and coding best practices like KISS, YAGNI, DRY, etc.
- Developed a tool that alerted me whenever a student requests a review so that I can give them support and this increased my productivity by 50%.
- Awarded the best collaborator of the month award due to my commitment to collaborating with students to improve their code quality.
- Helped students embrace the progressive enhancement methodology and now some of them are building scalable production-ready websites.

## Self-employed

Kigali, Rwanda

#### Full-stack web developer

May 2022 - Present

- Initiated and built FAMA software prototype. Software that connects farmers and agribusiness entrepreneurs so that they can trade without borders.
- Developed, tested, debugged and documented 20+ projects with different complexity and versatility. These include landing pages, CMS, web apps, and REST APIs using Ruby on Rails.
- Performed cross-browser testing and remediation for 100% of front-end web applications to ensure performance and superior quality.
- Collaborated with 40+ fellow developers on 50+ projects with different complexity where 90% of them, I was project manager, dividing tasks among the team, and tracking the progress till project delivery.

#### **JUUBIX**

London, UK(Remote)

## Front-end Developer

January 2022 - May 2022

- Demonstrated expertise in translating the client's specific needs into easy-to-understand software solutions during onboarding presentations, achieving over 80% customer satisfaction.
- Collaborated with agile team of 6 and helped prioritize and scope feature request to ensure that the biggest impact features were worked on first.
- Built a Landing page with outstanding animation using React and Framer motion which improved the time
  on page for average user by 2 minutes.

## **MICROVERSE**

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

November 2021 - Present

- Mentored 4 junior web developers, providing 1 hour per week in order to give them technical support, teach them coding best practices and effective remote working with diverse groups of people.
- Engaged my mentees in 1:1 discussions, small groups and breakout sessions where I provided tips and hints about code optimization which improved their websites' overall performance and code quality.
- Helped them learn different debugging techniques which increased their productivity by 30% as they no longer exceeded the project deadlines.

ITECH LTD Kigali, Rwanda

#### Junior Frontend developer Intern

January 2021 – October 2021

- Partnered with 2 Frontend developers to understand user stories and reported findings, goals and progress to senior engineer.
- Optimized 15+ applications for maximum speed and scalability.
- Collaborated with 4 design team members to implement innovativ solutions for product directly.
- Transformed 10+ visual components into web applications that were responsive, semantic and accessible.

# **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE October 2021 – July 2022

## Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1500+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and agile full-stack development technologies while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Provided some technical support to improve project documentation and the curriculum.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Rwanda Coding Academy

October 2021 - Dec 2021

## Web development program

- Developed a project that was rated among the top 5 software that can be turned into a profitable business.
- Provided support in developing proposals and project documentation.
- Awarded best collaborator award.